Mario Diaz

Rio Rancho, NM 87124 (505) 702-6159 Xavi.jr23@gmail.com and mdiaz20@cnm.edu

Skills

<u>Computer Experience:</u> Access, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, and Word. Tandem, Red Prairie, Management Console, Backhaul Report, and EZ claims.

Warehouse: Load, selecting, forklift, driver check-in, investigated shorts, receiving and clerical duties.

<u>Leadership Abilities:</u> I help manage the flow of getting the trucks out on time by directing work in the warehouse. Collaborated with management in coordinating the work schedule. Trained employees in selection, loading, forklift, receiving, driver check-in and clerical.

Experience

May 2019 - PRESENT

US Foods, Albuquerque-Shipping/Receiving Clerk-Lead

- Prepare inbound documents and assign receiving doors for inbound drivers.
- Enter all Purchase orders and verify all PO's have been cleared by end of day.
- Manage discrepancy report.
- Schedule all backhauls by coordinating with the buying department; prepare weekly backhaul report.
- File out of stock and damage claims.

January 2019 - April 2019

US Foods, Albuquerque - Receiver

- Check inbound product identification against invoices and receiving paperwork to insure correct pack/size, quantity, product quality and temperature, pallet ti/hi.
- Check temperatures of all inbound frozen and refrigerated products to ensure proper temperatures and comply with food safety and RRE requirements.
- Verify Quantity of each product to ensure the count matches the documentation; report any variances so that inventory levels are accurately adjusted in system.

January 2016 - December 2018

US foods, Albuquerque - Day Warehouse Forklift

- Letdowns in each department; Cooler, Dry, and Freezer.
- Put-aways in each department, Cooler, Dry, and Freezer.
- Selected Will calls.
- PIR put-aways.
- Per Joshua Robertson (previous VP of operations), I helped with driver check-in for about a month before they hired someone for the position.
- ICPM-Helped other US Foods in the nation in selection and Forklifting. Topeka, Norcross, St. Louis, and Columbia.

January 2015 - December 2015

US Foods, Albuquerque- Night Warehouse Selector

- Selection in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Forklift in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Load trailers.

July 2012 - December 2014

US Foods, Albuquerque- Night Warehouse Forklift-Lead

- Various tasks throughout the night: clerk, loading, selecting, and forklift.
- Driver check-in routes from El Paso and Las Cruces.
- Occasions when supervisor or manager had day the day(s) off, I would either open or close the shift.
- Opened and closed the Friday shift.
- Trained employees in loading, selection, and forklifting.

March 2004 - June 2012

US Foods, Albuquerque- Night Warehouse Selector

- Selection in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Forklift in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Load trailers.

Education

August 1997 - Current

University of New Mexico, Albuquerque - In progress

- Major: Bachelor of Science in Chemistry.
- Minor: Computer Science in Programming.
- No degree accumulated 115 credit hours.